（孟买  2006年）
贾马尔・马利克再答对一个问题 就可以赢得二千万卢比的奖金. 他是怎么做到的？
名字
Name.
(A：他作弊)
(B：他运气好)
(C：他是天才)
(D：命中注定)
各位 晚上好
Good evening...
欢迎来到《谁想成为百万富翁》节目现场
Welcome to Who Wants to Be a Millionaire?
准备好了？
Are you ready?
- 让我们以热烈的掌声欢迎…
- Please give a big round of applause...
- 小子 祝你好运
Good luck, kid.
今晚的第一位挑战者…
To our very first contestant of the night...
来自我们孟买本地的 贾马尔・马利克！
Jamal Malik, from our very own... amchi Mumbai!
走吧 开始玩了
Chalo, let's play.
微笑，你行的
Smile. You'll be fine.
姓名
Name.
姓名    贾马尔…马利克
Name. - Jamal... Malik.
你有名字 很好
You have a name. Good.
不准哭
Stop crying.
谢谢，谢谢
Thank you. Thank you.
谢谢 谢谢 非常感谢
Thank you. Thank you. Thank you very much.
贾马尔…跟我介绍一下你自己
So, Jamal...tell me something about yourself.
我在呼叫中心工作 在乔合
I work in a call center.  In Juhu.
很好
Good.
是个接线员
A phone basher.
是什么样的呼叫中心？
And what type of call center would that be?
XL5手机客服中心
XL 5 mobile phones.
哦 这么说 你是每天给人打电话推销手机服务的 对吧？
Oh.So you're the one who calls me up every singleday of my life with special offers,huh?
不 实际上 我只是个助理
No. Actually, I'm an assistant.
接线员助理？
An assistant phone basher?
接线员助理是做什么的？
And what does a assistant phone basher do exactly?
我给人泡茶…
I get tea for people and...
茶水工 一个茶水工！
Chai wallah. A chai wallah!
女士们 先生们…
Well, ladies and gentlemen...
来自孟买的贾马尔・马利克
Jamal Malik...
...《谁想成为百万富翁》现在开始
...from Mumbai, let's play Who Wants to Be a Millionaire
他有没有认罪？
So, has he confessed yet?
除了名字 什么也没问出来
Except his name, I could not get anything out of the runt.
你他妈一晚上都干什么了 斯里涅瓦斯？
You have been here a whole bloody night, Srinivas. What have you been doing?
他是个硬骨头
He's a tough guy.
给他来点电 他会松口的 快
A little electricity will loosen his tongue. Give him.
是，长官
Yes, sir.
快说 是不是有人帮你作弊？
Okay. So, were you wired up?
用手机 传呼机？
Mobile or a pager?
扮现场观众，咳嗽提示？
A coughing accomplice in the audience...
还是身上装了微芯片？
or a microchip under the skin?
这里没芯片 - 没有？  - 没有 - 行了 别管芯片了
The chip is not here.Not here? No.Okay. Leave the chip. Leave the chip. Leave the chip.
天这么热…我老婆又跟我过不去…
It's hot...and my wife is giving me hell...
每天还要面对杀人犯 强奸犯 勒索犯
and I've got a desk full of murderers, rapists,extortionists,
流氓抢劫犯 还有你
bum bandits and you.
我看我们还是为彼此 都省点时间吧
So why don't you save us both a lot of time...
快说你是怎么作弊的
...and tell me how you cheated.
电完了 长官
I'm done, sir.
听着
Now, listen.
喂？
Hello.
又晕过去了 这有什么用？
He's unconscious, Juti. What good is that?
跟你说了多少次了 斯里涅瓦斯？
How many times have I told you, Srinivas?
对不起 长官
I'm sorry, sir.
国际特赦组织看到了 又要被这里的人权吓得屁滚尿流了
Amnesty International here next, peeing in their pants about human rights.
长官 我在想…
Sir, I was thinking, um...
- 把他放下来 弄弄干净 帮帮忙 看在上帝的份儿上 - 长官…
- Get him down, tidy him up, please, for God's sake! - Sir...
万一他真的知道答案呢？
what if he did know the answers?
教授、医生、律师 百科专家…
Professors, doctors, lawyers, general knowledge wallahs...
最多也赢不过一万六卢比，他都快上千万了
never get beyond 16,000 rupees.He's on 10 million.
穷小子他妈的知道什么？
slumdog possibly know?
知道答案
the answers.
我知道答案
I knew the answers.
《贫民窟的百万富翁》
贾马尔 接住！接住！
贾马尔
贾马尔 看你的了！
我靠 这你都能接丢了？
离开这里！
抓住他！
差狗来了 快跑！
飞机撞不死你们 我整死你们！
哥哥！
#我们跑路 兵分两路 飞快的速度 别想把我们抓住 #
# They can't touch me We break off, run so fast they can't even catch me #
#我们是流浪汉 抓我吧 我轻松把你来耍#
# Been that gypsy Touch me, I show you tricks with my sticks that quickly #
#我一路顺手牵羊#
# Pick up their packs on myjourney #
#狗儿跟着我跑 我有我的运道#
# Dogs run They start to follow me I have my luck #
#偶尔把他们整倒 为了全家老小 找来生活钞票#
# Some days they suck when we live for the buck we get for the family #
#希望我也成为明星 也去酒吧逛逛#
# One day I wanna be a star so I get to hang in a bar#
#去把赌城闯闯 只为忘却我那一身伤#
# I'll go to Vegas if they pay us just to forget my scars #
对不起…
Sorry.
对不起，对不起
Sorry. Sorry.
对不起
Sorry!
#别想把我们抓住 我们兵分两路#
# They can't touch me We break off #
# 飞快的速度 别想把我抓住 #
# Run so fast they can't even catch me #
# 我们是流浪汉 抓我吧 #
# Been that gypsy Touch me #
#我轻松把你来耍#
# I show you tricks with my sticks that quickly #
哦 坏了 是妈妈…
看我不打你们个半死
大哥 把他们交给我吧
快走
- 埃索斯！ - 埃索斯！
- Athos! - Athos!
- 两个火枪手喊道 - 火枪手
- Cried the two musketeers. - Musketeers.
- 埃索斯！ - 埃索斯！
《三个火枪手》
重复一遍 “你找我 长官”埃索斯说
Repeat it. "You have sent for me, sir, '"said Athos.
- 你找我 长官 - 啊
"You have sent for me, sir." - Ah.
我们的火枪手来了
你们两能来上课 真是让我们大家受宠若惊呐
波索斯！
把书打开 萨利姆
别玩了 把书打开 贾马尔
埃索斯！
怎么样…
So...
马利克先生
Mr. Malik...
我们的万事通…说吧
the man who knows all the answers …Talk.
叫你说话呢
Talk.
贾马尔…
So, Jamal...
第一题 1000卢比 准备好了吗？
are you ready for the fiirst question for 1,000 rupees?
准备好了
Yes.
坐着答个问题就能拿钱 还不错吧
Not bad money to sit on a chair and answer a question.
比给人泡茶好赚吧 不是吗？
Better than making tea, no?
不是
No.
是，不是
Yes. No.
不是、是、不是？
No? Yes? No?
这就是你的最终答案吗？
Is that your fiinal answer?
记住 你有三次求助机会
So, remember, you have three lifelines.
请教现场观众
Ask the audience,
去除2个错误答案…
fiifty-fiifty...
给朋友打电话
phone a friend.
第一题 1000卢比
So the fiirst question for 1,000 rupees.
开始
Here we go.
1973年热门影片《囚禁》的主演是谁？
Who was the star in the 1973 hit film Zanjeer?
这下糗大发了 来…
给你
钱，拿去…
贾马尔 快出来 布拉卡要开个大的
我还没好呢
小子 快点 我这很急啊…
我还没屙出来呀
什么时候开始 拉屎也要限时了？
小子 我这都快出来了 你快点…
有客人在等 贾马尔你快点
把钱还给我 快！
我去别处好了
笨蛋！
你害我丢了一个客户
阿密塔的直升机！
是阿密塔的直升机！
阿密塔？
Amitabh?
阿密塔・巴查！
萨利姆，开门！
Amitabh Bachchan!
萨利姆！
Salim!
阿密塔・巴查！
Amitabh Bachchan!
阿密塔！
Amitabh!
走开！
请等一等
阿密塔先生，请给我签个名
太好了！阿密塔先生的签名呀！
你拿到签名？
阿密塔的签名？
是我的签名！
阿密塔签给我的！
下次再也要不到了
人家出了个高价 所以我把它卖了
但这是我的…
A：阿密塔・巴查！
"A. '"Amitabh Bachchan.
回答 正确 你将获得1,000卢比奖金
Guess what. You're right. You just won 1,000 rupees.
你不一定要是个天才
You don't have to be a genius.
我也知道是阿米达・巴查
I knew it was Amitabh Bachchan.
我说过，不一定要是个天才
Like I said, don't have to be a genius.
他是全印度最出名的人
He's the most famous man in India.
印度国徽上有三只狮子
Apicture of three lions is seen in the national emblem of India.
下面写着什么？
What is written underneath?
A：唯真理获胜…
"A," the truth alone triumphs...
B：唯谎言获胜…
"B," lies alone triumph...
C：唯时尚获胜…
"C, '"fashion alone triumphs...
D：唯金钱获胜
"D," money alone triumphs
答案是什么 贾马尔？
What do you think, Jamal?
我国最有名的名言
The most famous phrase of our country.
要给朋友打电话吗？
Would you like to phone a friend?
求助现场观众
Ask the audience.
女士们 先生们 帮帮这个可怜人吧
Put the poor man out of his misery, ladies and gentlemen.
连我五岁的女儿都知道
My five-year-old daughter can answer that question,
但你不知道
but you couldn't.
对一个赢得百万奖金的天才来说 是不是有点奇怪呀
That's strange for a millionaire genius.
怎么了？你的同伴溜出去上厕所了？
What happened? Your accomplice nip out for a piss?
探长问你话呢
The inspector is asking something.
在焦佰蒂街哈里什店里的 巴里布里多少钱一个？
How much is pani puri at Harish's stall on Chowpatty?
什么？
What?
巴里布里 一盘 多少钱？
Pani puri. One plate, how much?
十卢比    错
- Ten rupees. - Wrong.
排灯节以来十五卢比了
Fifteen since Divali.
上星期四在圣克鲁斯车站是谁偷了康斯特・万马斯的自行车？
Who stole Constable Vermaas's bicycle outside Santa Cruz station last Thursday?
你知道是谁吗？
You know who that was?
在乔合所有人都知道
Everyone in Juhu knows that.
包括五岁小孩
Even five-year-olds.
祝贺你 贾马尔 你的奖金已经累计到4,000卢比了
Congratulations, Jamal. You just won 4,000 rupees.
下一题奖金是一万六千
For 16,000 rupees.
宗教，很有趣
Religion.Interesting.
在关于先神罗摩的描述中…
In depictions of God Rama...
他右手中握着的是什么？
he is famously holding what in his right hand?
嘿 贾马尔
Hey, Jamal.
他们是穆斯林 打啊！
贾马尔
Jamal...
快跑！跟上！
快！跟我们来！
嘿 滚开
聋了啊？叫你滚！
跟我们走！
每天早上醒来 我都希望自己不知道这个问题的答案
I wake up every morning wishing I didn't know the answer to that question.
要不是罗摩和阿拉…
If it wasn't for Rama and Allah...
我妈妈也不会死
I would still have a mother.
是弓和箭
A bow and arrow.
最终答案？
Final answer?
最终答案
Final answer
嗯 啊 电脑锁定答案D
Hmm. Ah. Computer-ji, "D'"lock kiya-jaye.
你刚刚赢得一万六千卢比的奖金！
You've just won 16,000 rupees.
答得不错 我的朋友
Well done, my friend.
下面进一段广告 不要走开
Time for a commercial break. Don't go away now.
运气不错 啊？
You got lucky, huh?
如果我是你 我就拿上钱走人了
If I were you, I would take the money and run.
下一题你肯定答不对的
You're not gonna get the next one.
还有90秒 所有人各就各位
Everybody back in 90, please. Okay?
请回位控制现场 谢谢
Can you come and do the controls, please?
滚开！
她会把保安招来的
让她进来吧
她可以当第三个火枪手
现在家里我最大 我说了她不可以进来 知道吗？
万一…
我们连那该死的 第三个火枪手叫什么都不知道
萨利姆
Salim.
过来吧
过来
你妈妈呢？
你爸呢？
我叫贾马尔
这是我哥哥萨利姆
我叫拉蒂卡
你喜欢的话 可以睡这里
谢谢你，贾马尔
欢迎回到《谁想成为百万富翁》节目现场
Welcome back to Who Wants to Be a Millionaire?
今天的挑战者 来自孟买的接线员贾马尔・马利克…
Our contestant, Jamal Malik, call center assistant from Mumbai...
已经获得16,000卢比的奖金 目前已经使用了一次求助机会
is on 16,000 rupees and has already used one lifeline-
向现场观众求助
ask the audience.
朋友 奖金越来越可观了
So, my friend, you're into serious money.
继续吗？
是
Yes.
歌曲《让我看看你》 是哪个著名印度诗人写的词？
The song "Darshan do Ghanshyam" was written by which famous Indian poet?
A：苏达斯  B：拓斯达斯
C：米拉拜  D：卡贝
贾马尔！
你好
Hello.
天气热吧？
It's hot, huh?
耶
Yea!
看他照顾我们的样子 他肯定是个好人
肯定是个要命的圣人
他不让我们和别人说话的
为什么？
要是知道为什么 那他就真是圣人了
阿尔文
# Darshan do Ghanshyam #
唱得很好，阿尔文 很好
萨利姆
Salim.
# Darshan do Ghanshyam #
敢笑我，我杀了你
嘿 放开她
别他妈碰我！
你这个死胖子！
你这棵大树
布诺斯 我看他就是你要找的帮手了
好了 走吧 开工了
带你们来这里郊游的吗？
让你们来干嘛的 度假啊？
笑什么笑？
交给我
不许哭！
哥哥
什么事？小兄弟 你有病啊？
抱住 今天你负责带她
我不带
抱着吧 这是为你好 有小孩可以要双份
她说了不想带她
你少说话 贾马尔！
接着 不然我把她扔下来了
就让她这么哭着 你可以要到三份
不准偷懒！开工！
你们想怎样？走开！
要最辣的
啊？
Huh?
老二粘到辣子了！
嘿
Hey.
你跑不了的！
都给我回去睡觉！
# Darshan do Ghanshyam #
很好
我很高兴
他可以了
我也准备好了
过来 把灯拿开
好了
萨利姆
Salim.
带贾马尔过来
贾马尔
Jamal.
给我听着 小子 你想想
你是想当一辈子穷光蛋
还是想当个响当当的汉子 啊？
真汉子 一个战士
你的命运是掌握在 你的手里的 兄弟
你可以像我一样
要不然…
明白吗？
明白
行了 去叫贾马尔
布诺斯
Punnoose.
我只想让马曼喜欢我唱的歌 我们就发财了
发大财了 拉蒂卡
然后呢？我们可以不用去要饭了吗？
要饭？你开什么玩笑？
我们去海滨路上买个大房子
你 我 还有萨利姆 我们是三个火枪手
海滨路？真的？
真的
在月光下…
你、和我
你会和我一起跳舞的 对吧？
希望你唱歌能比你跳舞好一些…
贾马尔
Jamal.
轮到我了
好好唱
轮到我了 啊 哥哥？
好日子要开始了
埃索斯
颇索斯？
按我说的
贾马尔
Jamal.
该让你成为专业歌手了
什么？真的？
首先 把那首歌唱给我听听…
那首《让我看看你》
我最喜欢听的
# Darshan do #
50卢比
现在我是专业歌手嘛 就这个价
臭小子
拿去
# Darshan do Ghanshyam #
Darshan do Ghanshyam #
贾马尔 快跑！
站住！
抓住他们！
取火把来！
拉蒂卡 快跑！
萨利姆!
Salim!
贾马尔!
Jamal!
快 拉蒂卡 抓住他的手！
拉蒂卡
Latika.
Latika
到底怎么回事？怎么回事？
她自己松手的
萨利姆!
Salim!
我们得回去 哥哥 我们得回去
回去我们就死定了
你疯了？
他要把你的眼睛挖出来！
用勺子挖
不用为她担心
她不会有事的
她从来都很命大
苏达斯
Surdas.
苏达斯？
你确定吗？
apka fiinal answer?
是的
Yes.
你猜怎么样？
Guess what.
回答正确！
You're right!
瞎眼乞丐可以多要一些 你知道的
那女孩怎么样了？ 他们把她也弄瞎了？
What happened to the girl? They blinded her too?
他们还有别的手段 我也是很久以后才发现的
They had other plans.It took me a long time to find out.
忘记她吧
来吧
去哪里？
该去弄点儿吃的了
#像纸一样 在天上飞翔#
# I fly like paper get high like planes #
-#在边境你把我拦住#
# If you catch me at the border#
# 我有签证在我手上 如果你跟我来#
# I got visas in my name If you come around here #
#这就是我的工作 签证立等可做#
# I make 'em all day I get one done in a second if you wait #
#像纸一样 在天上飞翔#
# I fly like paper get high like planes #
#在边境你把我拦住 我有签证在我手上 #
- If you catch me at the border I've got visas in my name #
#如果你跟我来 这就是我的工作 #
# If you come around here I make 'em all day #
#签证立等可做#
# I get one done in a second if you wait #
再见！
Bye Bye!
#坐在火车上 我常常畅想#
# Sometimes I think sittin'on trains #
#每到一个地方 我都在继续着这场比赛#
# Every stop I get to I'm clockin'that game #
# 大家都是胜者 我们闯出我们的名堂#
# Everyone's a winner We're makin'our fame #
#我们是实诚的生意人 确立着我们的名声#
# Bona fide hustler I'm makin'my name #
# 坐在火车上 我常常畅想#
# Sometimes I think sittin'on trains #
#每到一个地方 我都在继续着这场比赛#
# Every stop I get to I'm clockin'that game # - Yea!
#大家都是胜者 我们闯出我们的名堂#
# Everyone's a winner We're makin'our fame #
# 我们是实诚的生意人 确立着我们的名声 #
- Bona fide hustler I'm makin'my name #
嘿
Hey.
起来！
下去
这是你家的火车啊？
# Pirate skulls and bones #
# Sticks and stones and weed and bombs #
# Running when we hit 'em #
# Lethal poison through their system #
# Pirate skulls and bones #
# Sticks and stones and weed and bombs #
# Running when we hit 'em #
# Lethal poison through their system #
# No one on the corner has swagger like us #
# Hit me on my banner prepaid wireless #
# We pack and deliver like U.P.S. Trucks #
# Already going hell just pumping that gas #
# No one on the corner has swagger like us #
萨利姆! 萨利姆!
Salim! Salim!
我们上天堂了？
Is this heaven?
你还没死呢 贾马尔
You're not dead, Jamal.
那是什么地方？是酒店吗？
What is it? Some hotel, huh?
泰姬陵被公认为莫卧儿建筑的 最杰出代表作
The Taj Mahal is considered the fiinest example of Mogul architecture.
…死于1631年6月17日 在分娩他们第14个孩子的过程中
...who died on June 17, 1631...During the birth of their 14th child.
泰姬陵于1648年前后完工
The Taj Mahal was completed around, uh, 1648,
动用了2万劳工
using a labor force of 20,000 workers
1980年它被联合国教科文组织确认为 世界遗产…
In 1980 it became a UNESCO World Heritage Site and was cited as the-
请跟我来…
If you would like to follow me...
（正式导游）我带大家去看蒙泰姬墓上 阿拉的99个名字
I will show you 99 names of Allah on Mumtaz's tomb.
请脱鞋参观
Please take off your shoes.
（请在这儿脱下你的鞋）
请问…
Please. Please.
下一批参观什么时候开始？
What time is the next tour?
我们赶时间
We are on a very tight schedule, you see.
下午还要去看德里红堡
Have to see the Red Fort this afternoon.
（导游）- 不 我… - 求你了…
- No, l... ...Please,
能不能现在带我们进去？我们知道只带我们两个
would it be possibleto show us around now? Obviously we understand that it costs more
费用会贵一点
for just the two of us.
当然可以 夫人
But of course, madam.
请跟我来
Please follow me.
泰姬陵是可兰国王…为他的妻子蒙泰姬而建的
The Taj Mahal was built by Emperor Khurram...for his wife Mumtaz.
她是世界上最美的女人
Was the maximum beautiful woman in the world.
所以 她去世以后 国王就决定要建造这个…
So, when she died, the emperor decided to build this...
五星级的大酒店 给所有来看她的人住
fiive-star hotel...for everyone who'd like to visit her too.
但他在1587去世了…
But he died in 1587...
当时酒店的房间和电梯都还没建好
before any of the rooms were built or any of the lifts.
但你们所见到的游泳池…
But the swimming pool, as you can see...
却按时以最流行的设计完成了
was completed on schedule, in top-class fashion.
你说的这些导游手册上都没有的
There's nothing of this in the guidebook.
导游手册都是又懒又笨的叫花子写的
The guidebook was written by a bunch of lazy, good-for-nothing Indian beggars.
哦
Oh.
这儿 先生太太 就是蒙泰姬的墓室了
And this, lady and gentleman, is the burial place of Mumtaz.
她是怎么死的？
How did she die?
- 车祸死的
- A road traffiic accident.
- 真的？
- Really?
连环撞车
Maximum pileup.
她是生孩子死的吧
I thought she died in childbirth.
没错 先生 她就是在去医院的路上出车祸的
Exactly, sir. She was on the way to hospital when it happened.
准备好了？ 不要动
Ready? Don't move an inch.
微笑
Smile.
泰国硬木  --您拿好 买鞋子了！
Unbreakable Thailand wood. -You take. Shoes!
鞋！美国名牌
American brands! Shoes!
# All I wanna do And a... #
鞋！
Shoes!
# Then take your money 'Cause all I wanna do #
#  And a... Then take your money #
# All I wanna do And a...#
# Then take your money #
# And a...#
- 微笑！
- Smile!# All I wanna do #
# And a... And take your money #
# All I wanna do And a...#
# Then take your money #
戴维德先生 这是全印度最大的 露天手工洗衣厂
This, Mr. David, is the biggest dhobi ghat in the whole of India.
真了不起
That's amazing.
快 我们过去看看
-Come on. Take a real good look at this.
有人说北方邦的每个人…
They say that every man in Uttar Pradesh...
身上穿的衣服 都至少在这洗过一次
is wearing a kurta that has been at least washed once out here.
赶快拆车
一级方程式！ 一级方程式！
Formula One! Formula One!
注意进站速度！ 要有舒马赫风格！
Pit stop ka speed! Schumacher ka style!
有奶牛 水牛…那处是什么？
The-The cows, the-the buffaloes. What are those over there?
走 走 快走
哦 见鬼
Oh, shit.
这他妈怎么回事？
What the hell happened here?
行了
Okay...
行了 行了
Okay! Okay!
住手 住手 听到没？我的天 你买了保险的嘛
Cool it! Cool it, will ya? Jesus.，You got insurance,don't ya?
你没事吧？
Are you okay?
你想看真实的印度 这下看到啦
You wanted to see a bit of real India, here it is.
- 行了！
- All right!
- 孩子 这是真正的美国
- Well, here is a bit of the real America, son.
给钱
哦 对了 对了 天呐
Oh. Yes, yes. Jesus.
拿着
Here.
- Eurydice #
在100美元的纸币上…
-On an American $ 100 bill...
印着哪位美国领袖的头像？
-there is a portrait of which American statesman?
A：乔治・华盛顿…
-"A," George Washington...
B：弗兰克林・罗斯福…
-"B," Franklin Roosevelt...
C：本杰明・弗兰克林…
-"C," Benjamin Franklin...
D：阿布拉罕・林肯？
-"D," Abraham Lincoln?
退出还是继续 贾马尔？ 由你来决定
-Pay or play, Jamal? You decide.
哦 我的天 他在看摄像机 他不知道
-Oh, God. He's looking at the camera. He hasn't got a clue.
要完了 各就各位
-This is gonna be a walk-away. Stand by.
不 他是想先玩他一下
-No. He's gonna play with him fiirst.
贾马尔
-Jamal.
平时上班经常见到百元美钞吧？
-Get a lot of $100 bills in your line of work?
那是我拿到的最少的小费
-The minimum tip for my services.
哦
- Oh.
现在我才知道为什么 我的手机话费那么高了
-Now I know why my cell phone bills are so high.
他们给茶水工的小费都是百元美钞
-They tip the chai wallah with $100 bills.
答案是C：本杰明・弗兰克林
-It's "C." Benjamin Franklin.
- 你是要继续 对吧？ - 我想我已经继续了 不是吗？
-- You're gonna play, huh? - I think I just have, haven't I?
那是 C 对吧？没错？
- You certainly have. "C, '"right? Right?
1000卢比上印的是谁？
-Who's on the thousand-rupee note?
我不知道
-I don't know.
你不知道？
-You don't know?
甘地
-Gandhi-ji.
哦 听说过
-Oh. I've heard of him.
跟我耍小聪明 我让你再尝尝过电的感觉
- Don't get clever or I'll get the electricity out again.
你看
-Look.
他们也没问我这个问题呀 我也不知道为什么
-They didn't ask me that question.I don't know why.
不如你去问问他们
- Ask them.
真是好笑 看来你对钱不是很感兴趣
-It's funny. You don't seem that interested in money.
事实上 你获得了…一百万卢比
-As a matter of fact, you have...one million rupees!
说说100美元的事吧
-Explain the $100 bill.
孟贝都已经变成孟买了
-Bombay had turned into Mumbai.
你怎么就不明白呢？
-Why can't you understand?
我不想再干这个了
-I'm sick of this now.
以前有个女孩住这儿 跟我差不多高
她叫拉蒂卡
不认识叫拉蒂卡的
鸡肉汉堡2个 薯条2份
Two chicken burgers, two fries,
芒果酸奶1杯 可乐1个
one mango lassi, one Coke.
矿泉水1瓶
-One mineral water.
西姆拉
-Shimla.
我要去焦佰蒂了 你去不？
-I'm going to Chowpatty, okay? Wanna come?
拜托 我看你有病吧
-For God's sake. You've got some disease.
逼着我来这个鬼地方…
-You forced me back to this shit hole...
丢下好朋友 好生活 好多钱…就为这个？
-we leave our friends, a good life, loads of money... for this?
- 我们回来找她 - 那是你
-- We came back to find her. - You did.
我他妈才不潘呢  孟买满大街都是为我萨利姆准备的妞
-I don't give a shit about her.Plenty of pussy in Bombay for Salim.
哦 是的 老大
- Oh, yes, sir.
星期六晚上 你回你的笼子里去吧…
-You should come back to the cages on Saturday night...
别到处找你那失去的爱了
-instead of go searching for your lost love.
我要去焦佰蒂
-I'm going to Chowpatty.
这个城里有1900万人 贾马尔
-There are 19 million people in this city, Jamal.
忘了她吧 她成历史了
-Forget about her. She's history.
先生好，
好心有好报 衷心祝福热心助人的善人
美元？
-Dollars?
多少？
一百块
-100.
你当我是傻子啊
真的 我用我妈妈的灵魂发誓
钱上是谁？是谁的画像？
是个老头
秃顶，边上留着长发 像个女孩
本杰明・弗兰克林
-Benjamin Franklin.
都长成大小伙了 贾马尔
真为你高兴啊
我很难过，阿尔文
-I'm sorry, Arvind.
你获救了 我的朋友
我没你那么好运
这是我俩唯一的区别
阿尔文 我一直在找…
马曼恨着你呢 快走
他从不忘旧帐的
我对不起拉蒂卡
她还活着 对不对？
活得风光呢
她在比拉街 他们都叫她樱桃
谢谢
-Thanks.
我会在你葬礼上 为你歌唱的
哦 对不起啊
- Oh. Sorry.
樱桃？
-Cherry?
怎么样？是不是她？
-So, is it her or not?
真性感啊 伙计
-She's sexy, man.
拉蒂卡！
-Latika!
- 什么人？ - 贾马尔？
-- Who is this? - Jamal?
- 我去拿包 - 什么人？想干嘛？
-- I'll get the bag. - Who are you? What do you want?
- 快！ - 你个笨小子！
-- Quick! - You stupid boys.
- 快 都装上 - 你们干嘛？
-- Come on. Pack it in. - What are you doing?
- 你怎么找到我的？ - 晚点再说 晚点再说
-- How did you fiind me? - Later. Later.
不 不用都带走
-No, not everything.
有本事你们走啊
-Get out, if you can.
- 钱 拿钱 - 快 快走
-- Take the cash. Take the cash. - Come on. We gotta go.
走 快走
-Let's go. Let's go.
我操
Shit.
看看 这是谁来了？
-Look who we have here.
你们好啊…
-Hello again...
贾马尔…萨利姆
-Jamal...Salim.
从不会忘记别人的长相
-Never forget a face.
对吧 布诺斯？
-Hey, Punnoose?
更别提是我的人了
-Especially one that I own.
你以为你们可以就这样进来 把我的宝贝带走？
-You really thought you could just walk in and take my prize away?
拉蒂卡 过来
-Latika, come.
知道这个小雏子值多少钱吗？
-Have you any idea how much this little virgin is worth?
- 吉老师 请继续 - 是 先生
-- Please continue, Master-ji. - Okay, sir.
- 把他们赶出去
- Get them out of here.
- 休想！
- No!
走！过去！
-Move! Get over there.
别傻了 萨利姆
-Let's not be foolish, Salim.
很重吧？ 给我吧
-Heavy, isn't it? Give it to me.
啊？
-Huh?
给我跪下 快！
-On your knees. Down!
你们两个，跪下！
-Both of you, down!
钱！
-Money!
钱你拿走
-You can have money.
给你…
-Here.
看！
-Look.
拿着 走吧
-Take it. Go.
和你的朋友一起远走高飞 我们不会追究的 好吗？
-Disappear with your... friend, and we'll forget all about this. Okay?
马曼从不忘旧帐
-Maman never forgets.
是不是？
-Isn't that right?
哦 马曼也可以有例外的 啊？
-Oh, Maman can make an exception, huh?
我不能冒这个险 马曼 对不住了
-I can't take that risk, Maman. Sorry.
快走
-Let's go!
不准动！
-Stay!
贾马尔！
-Jamal!
走、走
-Let's go! Let's go!
是谁…发明的左轮手枪？
-Who invented the revolver?
塞缪尔・科尔特
-Samuel Colt.
最终答案？
-Final answer?
最终答案
-Final answer
贾马尔・马利克...简直超乎想象
-Jamal Malik...you're on a dream run.
我的内心告诉我 你会赢更多，
My heart says you're gonna win more.
电脑…
-Computer-ji...
锁定答案A
-"A'"lock kiya-jaye.
真被我说中了 茶水工又答对了
-I was right.The chai wallah has done it again.
难以置信！
-Incredible!
服务员！
- Service!
接待员
- Reception!
嘿嘿！
-Oh!
找到些 - 等会儿
- Found something. - Stay there.
转过头去
Look away.
不许偷看
-I know if you're looking.
我没偷看
-No, I'm not.
萨利姆还在吗？
-Is Salim still there?
萨利姆呢？
-Where's Salim?
不知道
-Don't know.
你真是个好人 贾马尔
-You're a sweet boy, Jamal.
我要见贾维德
-I'm looking for Javed.
他没说要见你
-He's not looking for you.
我杀了马曼
-I killed Maman.
我要把你们也一起杀了
-And I'll kill you too.
别紧张
-Easy.
你真的把他杀了？
-Did you really kill him?
好
-Good.
我敌人的敌人就是我的朋友
-My enemy's enemy is a friend.
过来，朋友
-Come here, my friend.
嗯 我一直都在找像你这样的人
-Mm. I've been looking for someone like you.
你是为我才回来的
-You came back for me.
当然
-Of course.
我还以为你早就把我忘记了呢
-I thought you'd forgotten.
我从没有忘记过 一刻也没有
-I never forgot. Not for one moment.
我知道我会找到你的
-I knew I'd find you in the end.
我们命中注定在一起
-It's our destiny.
命中注定
-Destiny.
嘿
-Hey.
起来
-Come.
不 哥哥 你喝多了
-No, Brother. You've had a lot to drink.
我是老板 我是老大
-I am the elder. I am the boss.
你就听我一次  快出去
-For once you do as I say.Now get out.
来吧 我救了你的命 对不对？
-Come on. I saved your life, didn't I?
萨利姆 不要啊
-Salim, please...
我要杀了你！
-I'll kill you!
杀死你！
-Kill you!
我要杀了你！
-I'll kill you!
现在我说了算
- I am number one now.
萨利姆 ！
-Salim!
萨利姆 开门！
-Salim, open it!
闭嘴！
-Shut up!
这把科尔特点45在我手上 我叫你闭嘴！
-The man with the Colt.45 says shut up!
快走 不然老子 在你眉心开个窟窿
-Go now, or Gunmaster G-9 will shoot you right between the eyes.
别以为老子不敢
-Don't think he won't.
给你5秒钟 一…
-I'm giving you fiive seconds. One...
二…
-two...
走吧 贾马尔
-Go, Jamal.
走吧
-Go.
你有没有再见过他们？
-So, did you see them again?
要是见过 我也不会在这儿了
-I wouldn't be here if I had.
她漂亮吗？
-Was she pretty?
我猜大概不漂亮
-I guess not.
她是世上最漂亮的女人
-The most beautiful woman in the world.
他是说在贫民窟的婊子里最漂亮
-He means "the bitch of the slums."
嘿 嘿！
- Hey. Hey!
嘿 住手！
-Hey, no...
行啊 你
- Well, well.
贫民窟的狗也会乱咬
-The slumdog barks.
金钱和女人 是人生犯错的根源
-Money and women...the reasons to make most mistakes in life.
没错
-Correct.
看样子你两样都摊上了
-Looks like you're mixed up with both.
斯里涅瓦斯
-Srinivas.
你得活动一下了
-You need the exercise.
给我找点吃的来
-Go and get me something to eat.
是 长官
-Yes, sir.
还要茶
-And chai.
帕奥德
-Phaode!
笨蛋 斯里涅瓦斯
-Idiot, Srinivas.
小子 你把我搞糊涂了
-You puzzle me, slumdog...
承认杀人 也不想被起诉作弊…
-admitting murder to avoid the charge of fraud...
这可不是明智的想法呀
-is not exactly clever thinking.
为什么那样做？
-Now, why would you do that?
嗯
-Hmm.
别人问我问题…我就告诉他们答案
-When somebody asks me a question...I tell them the answer.
嗯
-Hmm.
你是怎么参加那个节目的？
-So, how did you manage to get on the show?
好了 各位 听我说
-Okay, everyone. Listen up.
上周英国发生了很多事情
-It's been a big week for U.K.
凯特回来了
-Kat is back.
她早就回来了
- But she was already back.
巴迪
Bardi.
贾马尔?
Jamal?
哦 是的 她是早就回来过 但她又走了…
-Oh, well, she did come back. Then she went away...
后来阿尔费和她分手了 她就又回来了
-when Alfiie split up with her, and now she's back again.
但看起来 阿尔费 还是更喜欢摩尔
-But it looks as if Alfiie still fancies Mo after all.
谢谢 贾马尔
-Thank you, Jamal.
巴蒂 加油啊 茶水工知道的都比你多
-Bardi, keep up.The chai wallah knows more than you.
另外 还有爱丁堡艺术节
-Anyway, there's also the festival in Edinburgh.
谁知道爱丁堡？ 爱丁堡？
-Anybody knows Edinburgh? Edinburgh?
呃， 苏格兰裙 城堡 嗯，羊杂  嗯， 本内维斯山
-Ah, kilts, castles, uh, haggis, uh, Ben Nevis.
很好 还有吗？
-Good. Yes?
泰戈特警官 威士忌酒 肖・ 康纳利
-Inspector Taggart, whiskey, Sean Connery.
很好 还有湖泊 他们对湖的叫法
- Good. And lochs- their word for lakes.
这里不许摄像
-No filming.
贾马尔 过来
-Jamal, come here.
今天我要上百万富翁
-I'm on Millionaire duty today.
- 戴夫 - 求你了
-Dave... Please.
就5分钟
Just for fiive minutes.
不行
-I can't.
坐下 要是头儿来了 你就假装是在接电话做升级
Sit here. If the team leader comes just pretend you are on a call doing an upgrade for...
- 给朋友和家人升级 我知道的
... Friends and Family. I know.
- 没错 - 2分钟
-- Yah. - Two minutes.
好
-Ah.
谁想成为百万富翁？
-Who Wants to Be a Millionaire?
赶快拨打这个电话
-Dial this number now.
回答这个问题 A.T.M.是什么…
-Answer this question. What does "A.T.M."...
喂？喂？喂？
-Hello? Hello? Hello?
我想参加 谁想成为百万富翁
-I would like to be a contestant on Who Wants to Be a Millionaire?
杂种，总是拨不通
-Bloody bastard. I never get it!
主持一说‘如果’  ，你就拨
-You have to dial when Prem says "if."
那时他们开始接线
- That's when they open the lines.
你怎么知道？
- How the hell do you know that?
技术部的安吉姆说的 系统是他装的
-That's what Anjum in technical says. He put the system in.
喂？喂？
-Hello? Hello?
拜托 又把我的电话转走了？
-Have I been transferred again, for God's sake?
喂？神仙保佑 来人接我电话呀？
-Hello? Good God, will somebody talk to me?
呃， 喂…
-Uh, hello...
麦金托什夫人，来自... 金…固…思
-Mrs. Mackintosh from..."King-uss-ie."
是吉内西 念吉内西
-It's Kingussie, love. Pronounced "Kingussie. '"
你是哪儿的？ 我看是国外来的
-So where are you from? Abroad, I bet.
就在你家那条路上 麦金托什夫人  呃， 就在湖的后面
Uh, just down the road from your house, Mrs. Mackintosh.Uh, next to the loch.
哦 是吗？ 哪个湖？
-Och aye? Which loch?
是…那个…
-Loch...
是…那个大的…笨湖
-Loch- Big... Loch Ben.
大笨湖 就在肖・ 康纳利家边上
-Loch Big Ben. Next door to Sean Connery's flat.
小子 我找你们领导说话
-I'd like to speak to your supervisor, son.
（连接断开）
（你需要什么名字？）
（拉O卡）
(搜寻结果：26283)
（萨利姆）
(搜寻结果：15)
（接线中…）
喂？
- Yes?
- 萨利姆？
- Salim?
哪位？知道现在几点了吗？
-Who is this? Do you know what time is this?
（中断）
喂？
-Hello?
哪位？
- Who is this?
先生 这里是XL 5通讯公司
-I'm calling from XL 5 Communications, sir.
作为我们的贵宾客户 我们免费为你提供服务升级…
-As a valued customer, we are offering you a free upgrade...
是给我们的朋友和…
-with our Friends and...
家人的
-Family...
贾马尔？是…是你吗 弟弟？
-Jamal?L-Is that you, Brother?
你在哪里？还以为你死了或出什么事了呢
-Where are you? I thought you were dead or something.
听我说 当时我们必须走 贾马尔
-Listen. We had to go, Jamal.
马曼的人 他们到酒店来找我们
-Maman's guys- they were searching the hotel.
贾马尔？
Jamal?
说话呀
Say something, please!
你好 萨利姆
-Hello, Salim.
剑桥广场不在剑桥
-Cambridge Circus is not in Cambridge.
知道是为什么吗？
-Dare I ask why?
太明显了
-Too obvious.
伦敦有一个牛津广场
-There's defiinitely an Oxford Circus in London.
牛津和剑桥有一个划艇比赛
And there's a rowing race between Oxford and Cambridge,
所以也许…
-so there's probably...
也有一个剑桥广场 不对吗？我选D：伦敦
-a Cambridge Circus too, no? I'll go for "D," London.
电脑锁定答案D
-Computer-ji, "D'"lock kiya-jaye.
贾马尔・马利克…
-Jamal Malik...
完全正确
-you're absolutely right!
现场的气氛正在逐步升温
-It's getting hot in here.
你紧张吗？
- Are you nervous?
什么？
- What?
我紧张吗？朋友 是你在接受考验
- Am I nervous? It's you who's in the hot seat, my friend.
哦 对
-Oh, yes.
对不起
-Sorry.
妈的 他开起主持人的玩笑来了
-Bloody hell, he's got Prem on the run.
- 总算是
- Finally.
几小时前…
- A few hours ago...
你还在给电话服务员倒茶
-you were giving chai for the phone wallahs.
现在 你比他们都有钱了
-And now you're richer than they will ever be.
真是厉害
-What a player.
女士们 先生们 多厉害啊！
-Ladies and gentlemen, what a player!
贾马尔？
-Jamal?
老天真伟大 老天真伟大
-God is good, bhai. God is good.
马曼的人在找我们 我们只能跑
-Maman's guys were after us. We just had to skip.
骗人！
- Liar.
- 我给你同事留了信息的 - 我们在那格浦尔等了你好几个星期
- Left a message for you at work. - Waited weeks for you at Nagpur.
- 没有信息
- - There was no message.
我肯定留了信息的
-Bhai, I defiinitely left a message.
没有信息 没有信息！ 没有信息！
-There was no message. There was no message! There was no message!
我永远不原谅你
-I will never forgive you.
我知道
-I know.
那里以前是我们住的贫民窟
-That used to be our slum.
你相信吗 啊？我们以前就住那 兄弟
-Can you believe that, huh? We used to live right there, man.
现在那里满地商机
-Now it's all business.
印度是世界交集的中心
-India is at the center of the world hub, bhai.
我在中心的中心
-I am at the center of the center.
这一切都是贾维德的
-This is all Javed-bhai's.
- 贾维德・ 康？ - 对不起
-- Javed Khan? - Sorry.
从我们那里出来的黑帮老大 你为他干活？
- The gangster from our slum? You work for him?
行了 你以为还有谁会愿意 从马曼手下救我们出来 啊？
-Come on. Who else do you think would save us from Maman's guys, huh?
你替他做什么？
-What do you do for him?
他叫干啥就干啥
-Anything he asks.
他快到了 你得走了
-He's coming. You need to go now.
- 拿上我的卡
- Take my card.
什么卡？
- What for?
你以为我还会让你 从我身边离开吗 啊？
-You think I'm gonna let you out of my sights again, huh?
从现在开始你和我一起 弟弟 走吧 去我那儿
-You stay with me now, younger brother.Now go- my place.
萨利姆 拉蒂卡在哪？
-Salim, where is Latika?
还想着她呐？
-Still?
她走了 弟弟 早就走了
She's gone, Brother. Long gone.
快走吧
Now go.
去我那儿
-Go to my place.
- 嘿 - 喂？
-- # Hey # - Hello?
好的 我马上过去
-Okay, I'll be right there.
哦 神啊，原谅我吧 我知道我自己所犯的罪恶
跟上
听我说
我是公司派来的新厨师
-I'm the new cook from the agency.
非常抱歉 让夫人久等了
-A thousand apologies.I am so late for the memsahib.
你等一下
-Just a minute.
抱歉…
-Excuse me.
这里不要厨师
-There's nothing about any cook.
只要一个洗碗工
-There is a dishwasher being delivered.
你知道该做什么吗？
-Do you know anything about that?
我就是你要的洗碗工
-I am your dishwasher.
贾马尔
-Jamal.
你看你
-Look at you.
我找到你了
-I found you.
你的脸怎么了  伤到眼睛了
-Your face.You've hurt your eye.
你来干嘛？
-Why are you here?
来见你
-To see you.
好吧 你看我
-Well, you see me.
然后呢？
-Now what?
C：伊甸园桥
-"C, '"Eden's Bridge...
D：苹果桥
-or "D, '"Apple's Bridge.
为什么每个人都喜欢这个节目？
-Why does everyone love this program?
这是一个逃脱的机会 不是吗？
-It's a chance to escape, isn't it?
进入另一个生活
-Walk into another life.
哦 我的天
- Oh, God.
贾维德会杀了你的 来 穿上
-Javed will kill you. Just- Here.
贾维德？你跟他在一起？
-Javed? You're with him?
一开始说要招洗碗工
-First you order a dishwasher.
现在又招了这个破厨子 啊？
-Now you want this fucking cook, huh?
- 我只是… - 闭嘴！ 球赛开始了
-- I just thought... - Shut up! The cricket is on.
你怎么看这种烂节目？
-And why do you watch this shit TV?
我已经是百万富翁了
-As it is I am a millionaire.
快 我饿了 给我做个三文治
-Come on. I'm hungry. Make me a sandwich.
我赌50万卢比 他能得一个百分跑
-I want to bet fiive lakh rupees he'll make a century.
赔率是多少？
啊 那就70万吧
-Ah! Make it seven then.
嗯 对
-Mm. Yeah.
跟我走吧
-Come away with me.
去哪里？靠什么生活？
-Away where? And live on what?
爱
-Love.
跟我走吧…就现在
-Come away with me... now.
坦督卡尝试破纪录
嗯！
-Mm!
别胡来！
Don't do anything!
萨利姆会帮我们的
-Salim will help us.
萨利姆？ 你还相信萨利姆？
-Salim? You still believe in Salim?
贾马尔 反正我很快就要走了
-Jamal, I'll be gone soon anyway.
我们很快就要离开孟买了
-We're getting out of Bombay.
去哪里？
-Where?
你以为他会告诉我吗？
-- Do you think he'd tell me? - No.
不是那第二个 不！不！不！
-Not the second- No! No! No!
这能算作是坦督卡的百分跑吗？
- And could that be a hundred for Tendulkar?
由第三裁判比利・ 伯顿来决定
- To the third umpire, Billy Bowden.
外野手继续
-Takes the fielder on.
球给得很深 投得不错
-In the deep. That's a good throw.
横击 看样子他非常有自信
-Flat. He looks confident.
没错 换我肯定不行
-Yeah, I wouldn't be.
鲍彻尔看起来非常 非常自信
-Boucher seems very, very confident.
这是什么狗屁？
-What is this shit?
滚
-Get out.
滚！
打出99分，功亏一篑 …
快走…不然他会把我们俩都杀了
-Now go... before he kills us both.
- 为我做件事好吗？ - 我愿做任何事情
-- You want to do something for me? - Anything.
那就忘记我
-- Then forget me.
什么？不行！
- What? No.
每天五点…我都会去维多利亚火车站等你 直到你出现
-I'll wait...at the V.T. Station 5:00 every day until you come.
我爱你
-I love you.
那又怎样？
-So what?
一切都太晚了 贾马尔 快走
-It's too late, Jamal. Now go.
贾马尔…
So, Jamal,
哪位板球手跑出了…历史上最精彩的百分跑？
which cricketer has scored...the most fiirst class centuries in history?
A：沙金・坦督卡
-"A," Sachin Tendulkar...
B：里奇・ 庞丁… C：麦克尔・ 斯拉特…
-"B," Ricky Ponting..."C," Michael Slater...
还是D：杰克・ 霍布斯？
-or "D,"Jack Hobbs?
记住 要是答错了…
-But remember, if you answer wrong...
就什么都没了
you lose everything
就像这样
- just like this.
继续吗？
-So do you want to do this?
好样的 贾马尔！
That's the way, Jamal!
诸多梦想…
- Dreams of so many...
随风飘落
-on the floor.
拉蒂卡！
Latika.
拉蒂卡…
贾马尔！贾马尔！
- Jamal! Jamal!
贾马尔！
- Jamal!
拉蒂卡！
- Latika!
求求你！
拉蒂卡！
- Latika!
女士们 先生们 广告时间到
- Time for a commercial break, ladies and gentlemen.
我知道 我知道 我跟大家一样很紧张
- I know, I know. I can't stand the tension either.
很快回来
-We'll be right back.
贫民窟出来的穷小子…一夜之间成为百万富翁
-Guy from the slums...becomes a millionaire overnight.
知道还有谁曾获此成功吗？
- Do you know who's the only other person who's done that?
就是我
-Me.
我知道这种感受  我知道你所经过的悲喜
- I know what it feels like.I know what you've been through.
我成不了百万富翁了  这题我不会
-I'm not going to become a millionaire.I don't know the answer.
之前你也说过这样的话
-You've said that before, yeah.
不 真的 这次是真的不知道
-No. Really. This time I don't.
别呀  你不能现在拿钱走人
-Come on. You can't take the money and run now.
你离历史仅一步之遥 小子
-You're on the edge of history, kid.
我也不知道我该怎么办
-I don't see what else I can do.
朋友 也许这都是命中注定的
-Maybe it's written, my friend.
我不知道…
-I don't know.
冥冥中我能感觉到 你会成功的
-I just get some kind of karmic feeling you're going to win this.
相信我 贾马尔  你会赢的
-Trust me, Jamal.You're going to win.
所有人各就各位 还有30秒直播开始
- Stand by, everyone. We're on live in 30.
快把他找回来 主持人已经到位了
- Get him back on the floor, yeah. Prem is waiting.
来了 来了 我看到他了
- Yeah, he's coming. He's coming. I'm just getting him.
这边请 20秒
-Go fiirst. Twenty seconds.
作一个正确的选择 3分钟之后 你就可以和我一样有名了
-Do the right thing, and in approximately three minutes, you'll be as famous as me.
10秒
-Ten seconds.
还可以和我一样…
And as rich as
有钱
me.
5秒…4…3…
-Five seconds. Four, three...
从小人物到大富翁 这是你的命
-From rags to raja. It's your destiny.
开始！掌声与音乐 谢谢！
-We are on! Applause and music, please!
摇臂镜头上 接2号
-Jib move out. Cut to two.
欢迎回到 《谁想成为百万富翁》节目现场
-Welcome back to Who Wants to Be a Millionaire?
今天坐在挑战席上的是贾马尔・马利克
-In the chair tonight is Jamal Malik.
- 对！ - 如果你还不知道的话
-- Yeah! - As if you don't know.
奖金将会是一千万卢比
-For 10 million rupees
我们再看一下题目
-The question once again:
哪位板球手跑出了 历史上最精彩的百分跑？
-Which cricketer has scored the most fiirst class centuries in history?
- 我知道肯定不是沙金・坦督卡
- I know it isn't Sachin Tendulkar.
- 开局不错啊
- That's a start.
所以 有可能是里奇・ 庞丁…杰克・ 霍布斯或者是麦克尔・ 斯拉特
-So it could be Ricky Ponting...Jack Hobbs or Michael Slater.
我用一次求助机会 去掉2个错误答案
-I'll use a lifeline- fiifty-fiifty.
好的 我们请电脑去掉2个错误答案
-Okay. Computer, take away two wrong answers, please.
看来 沙金・坦督卡，被你说中了
-Well, you were right about Sachin Tendulkar.
剩下二选一 贾马尔 B：里奇・ 庞丁…
-That leaves you a fiifty-fiifty choice, Jamal. "B," Ricky Ponting...
或者D：杰克・ 霍布斯
-or "D,"Jack Hobbs?
你选哪个？
-What do you think?
该作决定了，一千万卢比
- Decision time.For 10 million rupees.
选B：里奇・ 庞丁…
-"B," Ricky Ponting...
还是D：杰克・ 霍布斯？
-or "D, '"Jack Hobbs?
D
不选B?
-Not "B"?
B：里奇・ 庞丁… 澳大利亚伟大的板球手
-"B, '"Ricky Ponting...the Australian great cricketer?
D：杰克・ 霍布斯
-"D,"Jack Hobbs.
你认识他？
-You know?
那就有可能是B 里奇・ 庞丁
-So it could be "B," Ricky Ponting.
也可能是D 杰克・ 霍布斯
-Or "D,"Jack Hobbs.
最终答案
-Final answer-
D
电脑锁定答案D
-Computer-ji, "D. '" "D'"lock kiya-jaye.
锁定答案D 电脑锁定答案D
-"D'"lock kiya-jaye. Computer-ji, "D'"lock kiya-jaye.
曾打出…
-With...
197 个精彩百分跑 答案是…
-197 fiirst class centuries, the answer is...
D：杰克・ 霍布斯！
-"D,"Jack Hobbs!
贾马尔・马利克
-Jamal Malik
百万富翁！
-millionaire!
女士们 先生们 真不敢相信自己的眼睛
- I cannot believe my eyes, ladies and gentlemen!
跳舞庆祝一下 来吧 来吧
-This needs a dance, man! Come on! Come on!
干的好 干的好
-Well done. Well done.
那么 你准备好去答最后一道问题…
-So, are you ready...For the final question?
去赢取二千万卢比了吗？
-For 20 million rupees.
没有
-No.
不过，也许这也是命中注定吧 不是吗？
-But maybe it's written, no?
也许吧
-Maybe.
好的 谁想成为百万富翁的 最后一个…
-Okay, the final question on Who Wants to Be a-
节目时间到
真是精彩 女士们 先生们 真精彩！
-What a show, ladies and gentlemen.What a show!
明晚继续加入我们…
- Join us tomorrow night to see...
见证贾马尔・马利克犯下他这辈子最大的错误…
-if Jamal Malik has made the biggest mistake of his life or just won..
还是赢得印度电视直播历史上 最大的奖金
- the biggest prize in the history of Indian television.
- 这边请 - 对 我们…
-- This way. - Yeah. Let's just...
来 贾马尔
-Come, Jamal.
表现不错
-Great show.
明天见 好吗？ 准时来
-See you tomorrow, okay? Be on time.
- 好的 - 再见
-- Yeah. - Bye.
小心点
-Careful.
怎么了？
- What's going on?
- 他作弊 -
-- He's a cheat.
你怎么知道他作弊？
- How do you know he's cheating?
死鬼乡下佬
-Bloody village boy.
我给他一个错误答案 那小东西居然还是答对了
-I fed him the wrong answer, and that little shit got it right.
你给他答案？
-You gave him an answer?
确切说也不是
-Not exactly.
这很重要吗？ 这…这是我的节目  这他妈的是我的节目！
-But how does it matter? It's- It's my show. It's my fucking show!
勉强也能说得过去
-It is bizarrely plausible.
- 但是 - 因为我穷得叮当响 是个茶水工…- 所以我是骗子 对吧？
-- And yet - Because I'm a slumdog, a chai wallah...I'm a liar, right?
- 大多数情况下是
- Most of you are.
但你不是 马利克先生 这是可以肯定的
-But you are not a liar, Mr. Malik. That's for sure.
你太过真实了
-You're too truthful.
我问完了
-We're done.
我不知道他们把她带去哪了
-I don't know where they've taken her.
拉蒂卡
-Latika.
我去参加节目…是因为我以为她会收看节目
-I went on the show...because I thought she'd be watching.
贾马尔・马利克…一个来自孟买贫民窟 未受过教育的18岁男孩…
-Did Jamal Malik...an uneducated 18-year-old boy from the slums of Mumbai...
到底是靠公平手段 还是作弊赢得的1000万奖金？
-win one crore by fair means or foul play?
对于我周围的民众来说 他们还有一个更大的疑问
-In the crowd around me, there is an even bigger question.
他今晚是否还会参加节目 来赢取2000万卢比的奖金？
-Will he be back tonight to play for another 20 million rupees?
贾马尔・马利克
-Jamal Malik
[印度语]
嘿 你 过来 亲一个
-Hey, you, come here. Give me a kiss.
- 快过来 - 你叫我吗？
-- Come here. - You want it?
对 来一个 快！
-Yeah, I want it. Come on, girls!
听不清你说什么
快过来把我们接回城里
如果说一个选手一路过关斩将…直接杀入最后一关 还不够戏剧化的话
And if there wasn't enough drama in a contestant reaching the fiinal question,
贾马尔・马利克…昨晚被捕，- 警方怀疑他作弊
Jamal Malik...was last night arrested...- On suspicion of fraud.
那个家伙……他是从不会放弃的
- That guy...He will never give up.
从不会
-Never.
走吧
- Go.
可是…
- But...
只管走
-Just drive.
不会再有机会了
-There won't be another chance.
他会杀你
-He will kill you.
他那儿我来摆平
-I'll take care of him.
萨利姆，我不能…
-Salim.I can't.
你必须要走
-You have to.
看在上帝的份儿上，拿着这个
-For God's sake, hold on to this.
原谅我所做的一切
-And for what I've done, please forgive me.
好好活着
-Have a good life.
回去参加节目
-You're back on the show.
快呀！
-Come on!
- Come on.
贾马尔？那个有钱人？
身价好几百万 有很多钱的那个？
加油 孩子
我祝福你 你能赢的
我们都爱你 贾马尔
今晚整个国家都被这股 百万富翁热所感染…
- The nation is gripped with Millionaire fever tonight...
贾马尔・马利克 一个来自孟买乔合 没受过教育的年轻人…
-as Jamal Malik, an uneducated young man from theJuhu slum in Mumbai..
在一档《谁想成为百万富翁》的电视节目中…
-won a staggering 10 million rupees...
赢得了令人吃惊的 一千万卢比奖金
-on the television show Who Wants to Be a Millionaire?
估计多达九千万观众今晚会…
An estimated 90 million people will tune in tonight...
关注他是否会继续参加节目并赢得…
-to see if he can go one stage further and win...
超乎想象的二千万卢比奖金
-an unthinkable 20 million rupees.
快呀！
- Come on!
人呢？都回来
Where is everyone? Get back in here.
回来工作 快
-Get back to work. Now.
茶水工？
-Chai wallah?
欢迎回到《谁想成为百万富翁》节目现场
-Welcome back to Who Wants to Be a Millionaire?
我可以很肯定地说 今晚…将是你我人生中最重大的一个夜晚
I can safely say that tonight...is the biggest night of both our lives.
贾马尔・马利克 来自孟买的接线员…
-Jamal Malik, the call center worker from Mumbai...
已经赢得了一千万卢比的奖金
-has already won a cool 10 million.
他可以带上这些钱退出比赛…
-He can walk away with that in his pocket...
或者作一次电视史上最大的赌博…
-or make the biggest gamble in television history...
挑战最后一道题目…，赢取两千万卢比的巨奖
and go for the fiinal question..and a staggering 20 million rupees.
准备好了吗？
-Are you ready for that question?
- 准备好了 - 贾马尔！
-- Yes. - Jamal!
喜欢看书吗 贾马尔？
-Big reader, are you, Jamal?
我识字
-I can read.
很幸运
-Lucky.
大仲马的小说…
-In Alexander Dumas's book...
三个火枪手…
-The Three Musketeers...
其中两个火枪手名叫埃索斯和颇索斯
-two of the musketeers are called Athos and Porthos.
第三个火枪手的名字叫什么？
-What was the name of the third musketeer?
A：阿拉米斯
"A, '"Aramis,
B：卡迪纳・莱切里奥
"B, '"Cardinal Richelieu...
C：达塔安
-"C," D'Artagnan...
还是D：普兰切特？
-or "D," Planchet?
埃索斯！
-Athos!
她可以当第三个火枪手
最后一个问题 2000万卢比 而他却在微笑
-Final question for 20 million rupees, and he's smiling.
我猜你知道答案
-I guess you know the answer.
你相信吗？我不知道
-Do you believe it? I don't.
你不知道？
- You don't?
那你要带着一千万奖金 退出比赛吗？
-So you take the 10 million and walk?
不
-No.
我继续
-I'll play.
我提醒你 贾马尔
-Let me remind you, Jamal.
如果答错的话…
-If you get the answer wrong...
你会失去一切
-you lose everything.
一千万卢比啊 贾马尔
-Ten million rupees, Jamal.
很大一笔钱
-It's a fortune.
我要给朋友打电话
-I'd like to phone a friend.
我们要用最后一个 求助机会了 跟场外朋友连线
-We're going to the wire.The final lifeline.
开始
-Here we go.
电话响了
-It's ringing.
打给谁？
-Who is it?
号码是我哥的 但是…
-It's my brother's number, but...
- 可以带着2000万卢比的问题…出去散步的哥哥？
The kind of brother who'd go for a walk on a 20 million rupee question?
我就记得这一个号码
- It's the only number I know.
得靠你自己了 贾马尔
-You are on your own, Jamal.
喂？
-Hello?
喂 贾马尔？
-Hello, Jamal?
我猜这不是你哥
-I'm guessing that isn't your brother.
哪位？
-This is?
我叫拉蒂卡
- My name is Latika.
好的 拉蒂卡 你需要再听一遍题目吗？
-Okay, Latika. You want to hear the question one more time?
先说清楚
-And let's be clear about this.
二千万卢比就全看你的回答了
Twenty million rupees ride on your answer.
你有30秒
You have 30 seconds.
- 拉蒂卡！
-- Latika!
- 贾马尔…  请…
-- Jamal...- please ...
- 萨利姆！为拉蒂卡念一遍题目
-- Salim!  read out the questionTo Latika now.
真的是你？    是我
-Is that really you?- Yes.
- 题目 贾马尔 念题目
-- Yes. - The question, Jamal. The question.
大仲马的小说 三个火枪手里…
-In Alexander Dumas's book, The Three Musketeers...
两个火枪手的名字是埃索斯和颇索斯
-two of the musketeers are called Athos and Porthos.
第三个火枪手叫什么？
-What was the name of the third musketeer?
A：阿拉米斯
Was it "A, '"Aramis,
B：卡迪纳・莱切里奥  C：达塔安 D：普兰切特
"B, '"Cardinal Richelieu... "C," D'Artagnan, "D," Planchet?
15秒
- Fifteen seconds.
你在哪里？
- Where are you?
我很安全
-I'm safe.
10秒 拉蒂卡 答案是什么？
- Ten seconds. Latika, what do you think?
我不知道
-I don't know.
我一直不知道   贾马尔…祝你好运…
-I've never known.Jamal…good luck on you…
这下你真得靠自己了 贾马尔
-You really are on your own now, Jamal.
二千万卢比，你的最终答案
-Your final answer for 20 million rupees.
A
A，为什么？
-"A," because?
没有为什么
-Just... because.
嘿 萨利姆！
-Hey, Salim!
最终答案？
-  Final answer?
对，最终答案。A：阿拉米斯
-Yes. Final answer- "A," Aramis.
电脑锁定答案A
-Computer-ji, "A'"lock kiya-jaye.
萨利姆！
-Salim!
贾马尔・马利克
-Jamal Malik.
来自孟买的接线助手
-Call center assistant from Mumbai.
茶水服务员
-Chai wallah.
为两千万卢比
-For two crore-
两千万卢比
-twenty million rupees.
你的问题是在大仲马的小说里第三个火枪手的名字是什么
You were asked who the third musketeer was In the novel by Alexander Dumas.
你的回答是A
-You answered "A"...
阿拉米斯… 那是…
-Aramis...which is...
我要告诉你的…
-I have to tell you...
正确的回答！
the right answer!
贾马尔・马利克！
-Jamal Malik!
2000万富翁！
-Double crorepati!
神是伟大的
-God is great.
多么激动人心的夜晚！
-What a night!
女士们 先生们…我们在这里…
-Ladies and gentlemen...we are present here...
创造了…历史！
-to create... history!
干得好！
-Well done!
我知道你会看的
-I knew you'd be watching.
还以为我们这辈子 都不能再相会了
-I thought we'd meet again only in death.
这就是我们的命
-This is our destiny.
吻我
-Kiss me.
(D：命中注定)